Guide to the Jean Toomer Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1918-63; Series I; 4.25; (10 boxes)
  - JEAN TOOMER
    - Theatre Arts Magazine
      See: Box 5, folder 164
    - Thompson, George R.
      See: Box 2, folder 49
    - Thurston, Ethel
    - Toomer, Margery ("Argie"), 1949 (Box 8, Folder 249)
    - Toomer, Margery Latimer, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 250)
    - Toomer, Marjorie Content, 1934-53, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 251-61)
    - Toomer, Nina Pinchback, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 262)
    - "U" general, 1946-47 (Box 8, Folder 263)
    - "V" general, 1937-52 (Box 8, Folder 264)
    - Vassar College
      See: Box 5, folder 163
    - The Viking Press, Inc., 1929-34 (Box 8, Folder 265)
    - "W" general, 1922-51 (Box 8, Folder 266-67)
    - W. W. Norton & Company, Inc., 1937 Aug-Sep (Box 8, Folder 268)
    - Walcott, Eugenia B., 1929-54, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 269-73)
    - Walcott, Russell S., 1929-53, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 274-76)
    - Walker, Dorothy, 1932-54, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 277)
    - Walsh, Richard J., 1939 Jun (Box 8, Folder 278)
    - Walton, J. Barnard
    - Waring, Thomas, 1923-57 (Box 8, Folder 279)
    - Wertheim, Alma M., 1927-28 (Box 9, Folder 280)
    - Whitaker, C. H., 1930 Aug-Sep (Box 9, Folder 281)
    - White, Walter
    - Winchester, Harold P.
    - Wolfe, Edwin & Dorothy, 1945-58 (Box 9, Folder 282)
    - Wright, Mae & family, 1922-23 (Box 9, Folder 283)
    - The Writers' League Against Lynching, 1933-34 (Box 9, Folder 284)
    - "Y" general, 1937-47 (Box 9, Folder 285)
    - Zwaska, Paul Taylor
      See: Paul Taylor, Box 8, folder 247
    - Unidentified letters by first name, A-Z, 1918-58, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 286-90)
    - Unidentified letters and envelopes, 1923-63 (Box 9, Folder 291-92)
  - MARGERY LATIMER TOOMER
    - Baldwin, Louis Fremont, 1932 Mar-May (Box 9, Folder 293)
    - Barnes, G. Alfred, 1932 Jan 3 (Box 9, Folder 293)
    - Bentley, Edith, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 293)
    - Berger, John Van Eman, 1930 Dec 30 (Box 9, Folder 294)
    - Bliss, Caroline Mirza, 1932 May-Aug (Box 9, Folder 294)
    - Bragdon, Claude, 1931 Nov 2 (Box 9, Folder 295)
    - Carter, E., 1933 Feb 4 (Box 9, Folder 295)
    - Chambrun, Jacques, 1931-32 (Box 9, Folder 296)
    - Chase, Laura Greshemer, 1930-31 (Box 9, Folder 296)
    - Comfort, Jane, 1926-32 (Box 9, Folder 297)
    - Derleth, August W., 1930-32 (Box 9, Folder 298)
    - Driftmier, Lucille, 1932 Jul 24 (Box 9, Folder 299)
    - Dupee, Katherine Green
      See: Katherine Green, Box 3, folder 89
    - Dupee, Yvonne, 1931-32 (Box 9, Folder 299)
    - Gale, Zona, 1932 Aug 2 (Box 9, Folder 300)
    - Gerner, Mrs., 1932 Jul 29 (Box 9, Folder 300)
    - Goldman, Perry, 1930-32 (Box 9, Folder 301)
    - Grady, Daniel & Ruth, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 302)
    - Green, Katherine ("Tockie"), 1928-31 (Box 9, Folder 303)
    - Green, Mildred O., 1928-32 (Box 9, Folder 304)
    - Grove, Shirley, 1929-32 (Box 9, Folder 305)
    - Heath, Mrs., 1929-30 (Box 9, Folder 306)
    - Hergenhan, Mildred, 1922-30 (Box 9, Folder 307)
    - Irving Trust Company, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 308)
    - Johns, Richard, 1929 Aug 27 (Box 9, Folder 308)
    - Keck, Lucile L., 1932 Feb 22 (Box 9, Folder 308)
    - Kelm, William & Karlton, 1929-32 (Box 9, Folder 309)
    - Latimer, Clark Watt, 1921-31 (Box 9, Folder 310)
    - Latimer, Laurie Bodine, 1921-32 (Box 10, Folder 311-17)
    - Leighton, Lucy Ann, 1932 May 25 (Box 10, Folder 318)
    - LeSueur, Meridel, 1928-32, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 319-22)
    - Lieber, Maxim, 1930-32 (Box 10, Folder 323)
    - Littell, Mary, 1932 Aug (Box 10, Folder 324)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, [1932] Apr 23 (Box 10, Folder 324)
    - McClelland, Ruth, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 325)
    - Moody, Harriet, 1931 Oct 29 (Box 10, Folder 325)
    - Murison, Hilda, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 325)
    - Nashville Agricultural Normal Institute, 1932 Sep 30 (Box 10, Folder 326)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People
      See: Box 10, folder 330
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1928-29 (Box 10, Folder 327)
    - Otis, Raymond, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 328)
    - Overholt, Jessie, 1924-32 (Box 10, Folder 329)
    - Pickens, William, 1932 Mar 17 (Box 10, Folder 330)
    - Plater, Phyllis, 1930 Dec (Box 10, Folder 330)
    - Powys, John Cowper, 1930-31 (Box 10, Folder 331)
    - Rakosi, Carl, 1925-31 (Box 10, Folder 332)
    - Roberts, Sara, 1930-32 (Box 10, Folder 333)
    - Rogers, Marian & Samuel, 1929-32 (Box 10, Folder 334)
    - Schorer, Mark, 1929-32 (Box 10, Folder 335)
    - Scribner's Magazine, 1931 Nov 24 (Box 10, Folder 336)
    - Smith, Harrison, 1930-32 (Box 10, Folder 337)
    - Stewart, Camille, 1931 Nov 27 (Box 10, Folder 338)
    - Taylor, Zella, 1932 Jun 13 (Box 10, Folder 338)
    - Ware, Ruth, 1928-32 (Box 10, Folder 339-40)
    - Wilkeson, Mary J., 1931 Feb 7 (Box 10, Folder 341)
    - Unidentified, 1931-32, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 342)
- Writings, 1920-54; Series II; 20.5; (49 boxes)
  Boxes 11-59 hold Series II, Writings, which is divided into seven sections, Autobiographical Writings, Books, Drama, Essays and Lectures, Poetry, Reviews, and Short Stories. Each section is arranged alphabetically by title. Material within each title has been placed in the probable order of creation, established by comparing dates and analyzing the texts. All dates were taken from drafts. Manuscript titles appear in quotations; supplied titles do not. Some titles have been shortened. Well-known variant titles have been given cross-references. Unidentified or untitled drafts are filed at the end of each section. Essays and Lectures are divided into ten subjects, then arranged alphabetically by title. Published titles are used when known. Untitled essays and lectures are filed at the end of each subject division. In the Poetry section, folders often contain more than one title. Serials which contain poems are interfiled. Reviews are filed alphabetically by author of the work being reviewed or by title if the author is unknown. Short Stories include cross-references to stories contained in collections. Unidentified fragments are filed in folder 1400 at the end.
  - AUTOBIOGRAPHICAL WRITINGS
    - "America's Proposed Riviera"
      See: Box 19, folder 506
    - "Autobiographical Sketch"
      - Drafts, 1931-43, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 343)
    - "Book X"
      - "First Draft": holograph, 1935 Jan-Feb, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 344-57)
      - Second draft: typescript of prefaces & chapters 1-24, 1935 Feb-Mar (Box 11, Folder 358-66)
      - Second draft: typescript of chapters 25-32, 1935 Feb-Mar (Box 12, Folder 367-69)
      - Variant draft: typescript of chapter 1, 1935 summer (Box 12, Folder 370)
    - "Commissioned to Chicago"
    - "Earth Being"
      - Notes, 1930 Jul, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 371)
      - Early drafts, 1930 May-Jul, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 372-74)
      - First draft: copy 1 (incomplete), 1930 Sep, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 375-77)
      - "First draft": copy 2, 1930 Sep (Box 12, Folder 378-82)
      - Second draft (Box 12, Folder 383-87)
    - A Fiction and Some Facts
      - Drafts, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 388)
      - Pamphlets: 2 copies, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 389)
    - "From Exile into Being"
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 390)
      - First draft: holograph of chapters I-[IV], 1938 Feb (Box 13, Folder 391-94)
      - Second draft: holograph of chapters I-III, 1938 May (Box 13, Folder 395-98)
      - Third draft: holograph of chapters I-VII, 1938 Jun (Box 13, Folder 399-408)
      - Third draft: typescript of chapters I-VII, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 409-15)
      - Fourth draft: holograph of chapters I-II, 1938 Nov (Box 14, Folder 416-20)
      - Fourth draft: typescript of chapters I-II, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 421-26)
      - Fifth draft: typescript of part I- part II, chapter XIV, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 427-32)
      - Fifth draft: typescript of part II, chapter XV-part III, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 433-39)
      - Fifth draft: typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 440-44)
      - Draft fragments: part I, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 445-47)
      - Draft fragments: part II, 1939 Mar, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 448-53)
      - Draft fragments: part III, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 454-58)
      - Draft fragments: unidentified, 1937-38, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 459-68)
      - Draft fragments: unidentified, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 469-71)
      - Reader's report, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 472)
    - "Incredible Journey"
      - Notes
        - Foreword, 1941 Feb 17 (Box 17, Folder 473)
        - Chapter I. The Book of Family
          - Ancestry, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 474)
          - Father and Mother (Box 17, Folder 475)
          - The Pinchback Family, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 476)
          - My Life Begins: Jean Toomer, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 477)
        - Chapter II. The Book of the Garden, 1894-1906, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 478)
        - Chapter III. Book of the World Without, 1906-1909, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 479)
        - Chapter IV. Second Book of Washington, 1909-1914 (Box 17, Folder 480)
        - Chapter V. The Book of Exile, 1914-1919, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 481)
        - Chapter VI. The Book of Searching and Finding, 1919-1924 (Box 17, Folder 482)
      - Holograph fragments
        - Foreword, 1941 Feb, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 483)
        - Chapter I. The Book of Family
          - Ancestry, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 484-86)
          - Father and Mother: Nathan & Nina Pinchback Toomer (Box 18, Folder 487-91)
          - The Pinchback Family: William & Eliza Stewart Pinchback, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 492)
          - The Pinchback Family: P. B. S. Pinchback, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 493-95)
          - The Pinchback Family: Bismarck Pinchback, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 496)
          - My Life Begins: Jean Toomer, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 497)
        - Chapter II. Book of the Garden, 1894-1906, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 498-502)
        - Chapter VI. The Book of Searching and Finding, 1919-1924 (Box 19, Folder 503)
        - Chapter VII. [The Book of Gurdjieff and Chicago, 1924-30] (Box 19, Folder 504-06)
      - Typescript
        - Foreword, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 507)
        - Chapter I. The Book of Family, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 508)
      - Typescript, carbon
        - Foreword, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 509)
        - Chapter I. The Book of Family, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 510)
    - "On Being an American"
      - Holograph & fragments, 1934 Nov, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 511-12)
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 513)
    - "Outline of the Story"
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 514)
      - Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 515)
    - "The Second River"
      - Early typescript, 1943 summer (Box 20, Folder 516-23)
      - Typescript: chapters I-X, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 524-26)
      - Typescript: chapters XI-XXXVI, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 527-32)
      - Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 533-39)
      - Later typescript: chapters I-XIII, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 540-43)
      - Later typescript: chapters XIV-XXXVI, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 544-48)
      - Draft fragments: postscript, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 549)
      - Reader's report, 1944 Jun 10 (Box 22, Folder 550)
    - "The Second River"
      - Holograph, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 551-52)
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 553-56)
    - "Trace of a Life"
      See: Box 22, folders 551-52
    - "Why I Entered the Gurdjieff Work"
      See: Box 22, folders 553-56
    - Unidentified autobiography
      - Holograph, 1936 (Box 22, Folder 557-61)
  - BOOKS
    - Notes, 1937, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 562)
    - "The Angel Begori"
      - Draft, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 563-65)
      - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 566)
    - "As the World Revolves"
      - Notes, 1935-36 (Box 23, Folder 567-68)
      - Holograph: preface, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 569)
      - Holograph, 1936 May-Oct (Box 23, Folder 570-77)
      - Holograph, 1936 Nov-Dec (Box 24, Folder 578-81)
      - Holograph, 1937 Jan-Jul (Box 24, Folder 582-85)
      - Draft fragments: mostly holographs, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 586)
      - Draft fragments: mostly typescripts, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 587)
    - "A Book of Aims"
      - Notes, 1937-38, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 588-90)
      - Holograph: parts I-VIII, 1938 Jan-Feb, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 591-96)
      - Typescript: preface & introduction, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 597-98)
      - Typescript: parts I-VIII, 1938 Jan-Apr, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 599-601)
      - Typescript, carbon, 1938 Apr, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 602-05)
    - Cane
      - Typescript: foreword by Waldo Frank, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 606)
      - Page proofs, 1923 (Box 26, Folder 607)
      - Author's corrections, 1923 May 1 (Box 26, Folder 608)
      - Dust jacket, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 609)
      - Invoices and royalty statements, 1923-28 (Box 26, Folder 610)
      - Reviews, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 611)
      - Publicity, 1923-37 (Box 26, Folder 612)
    - "Caromb"
      - "First draft", 1932 Apr-Jul (Box 26, Folder 613-17)
      - Second draft, 1932, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 618-22)
      - Third draft, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 623-26)
    - "Co-opposition"
      - Notes, 1940 Mar-Apr (Box 27, Folder 627)
      - Holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 628)
      - Typescript, 1936-40 (Box 27, Folder 629)
    - "The Crock of Problems"
      - Holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 630-33)
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 634-35)
      - Typescript, carbon: copy 1, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 636-37)
      - Typescript, carbon: copy 2, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 638-39)
    - "Eight-Day World"
      - Early draft: chapters I-LX, 1933 (Box 28, Folder 640-46)
      - Early draft: chapters LXI-LXVI, 1933 (Box 29, Folder 647)
      - Early draft, carbon, corrected, 1933 Jun-Jul (Box 29, Folder 648-55)
      - Later draft: chapters I-XXXIX, 1935 (Box 29, Folder 656-60)
      - Later draft: chapters XL-LIII, 1935 (Box 30, Folder 661)
      - Later draft, carbon, 1935 (Box 30, Folder 662-67)
      - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 668)
    - Essentials
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 669-70)
      - Early draft, 1929 May 1, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 671-75)
      - Typescript I, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 676-77)
      - Typescript I, continued, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 678-80)
      - Typescript II: contents & introduction by Gorham Munson, 1930 (Box 31, Folder 681-82)
      - Typescript II: sections III-VIII, 1930 (Box 31, Folder 683-84)
      - Typescript III: contents & introduction, 1930 (Box 31, Folder 685-86)
      - Typescript III: sections I-VIII, 1930 (Box 31, Folder 687-89)
      - Typescript III, carbon, 1930 (Box 31, Folder 690-95)
      - Typescript IV, 1931 (Box 31, Folder 696)
      - Unidentified draft fragments, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 697)
      - Contract with printer, 1931 Feb 17 (Box 31, Folder 698)
      - Mailing lists, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 699)
      - Circulars, [1931] (Box 32, Folder 700)
      - Financial records, 1931 (Box 32, Folder 701)
      - Reviews, 1931 Mar-Jun (Box 32, Folder 702)
    - "The Gallonwerps"
      - Early draft, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 703-07)
      - Early draft, carbon: pages 1-310, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 708-12)
      - Early draft, carbon: pages 311-61, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 713)
      - "Final" draft, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 714-20)
      - "Final" draft, carbon, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 721-27)
      - Variant draft, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 728)
      - Variant draft, carbon, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 729)
      - Draft fragments: holographs, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 730)
      - Draft fragments: typescripts, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 731)
      - Publicity & proposed book cover design, 1931, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 732)
    - "Istil"
      See: "York Beach", Box 443, folder 900
    - "The Letters of Margery Latimer"
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 733)
      - Early draft variations: Introduction, 1934 Jul (Box 34, Folder 734)
      - Draft: Introduction & 1921-31, 1935 (Box 34, Folder 735-43)
      - Draft: 1932 & Index, 1935 (Box 35, Folder 744-46)
    - "Portage Potential"
      - Draft, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 747-50)
      - Publicity, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 751)
    - "The Possibilities of Human Growth"
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 752)
    - "Psychologic"
      - Notes, 1936 May-Sep (Box 35, Folder 753-54)
      - Holograph, 1936 Feb-Aug, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 755-61)
      - Holograph, continued, 1936 Aug, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 762-63)
      - Typescript, 1936 Oct 7 (Box 36, Folder 764-67)
      - Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 768-71)
    - "Psychologic Papers"
      - Holograph: A-I, 1936-37 (Box 36, Folder 772-81)
      - Holograph: J-W, 1936-37 (Box 37, Folder 782-95)
      - Typescript I: sections I-XIII, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 796-801)
      - Typescript I, carbon, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 802-07)
      - Typescript II: 1936 Jul-Dec, 1936-37 (Box 38, Folder 808-13)
      - Typescript II: 1937, 1936-37 (Box 39, Folder 814-16)
      - Typescript II, carbon, 1936-37 (Box 39, Folder 817-25)
      - Selections: typescript A, 1936-37 (Box 39, Folder 826)
      - Selections: typescript B, 1936-37 (Box 39, Folder 827)
      - Selections: typescript C, 1936-37 (Box 39, Folder 828)
      - Selections: typescript D, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 829)
      - Selections: typescript D, carbon, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 830)
      - Selections: typescript E, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 831)
      - Selections: typescript E, carbon, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 832)
      - Selections: German translation, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 833)
    - "Remember and Return"
      - Holograph, 1937 Jun-Dec, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 834-47)
      - Typescript: contents-Section XXVI, 1937 Dec (Box 40, Folder 848-54)
      - Typescript: sections XXVII-LIII, 1937 Dec (Box 41, Folder 855-57)
      - French translation: Introduction, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 858)
    - "Talks with Peter"
      - Notes, 1937 Jul-Aug (Box 41, Folder 859-61)
      - Notes, carbon, 1937 Jul-Aug (Box 41, Folder 862-63)
      - Holograph: sections I-XVI, 1937 Aug, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 864-71)
      - Typescript: sections I-XVI & fragments, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 872-75)
      - Variant draft: sections I-II, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 876)
    - "Towards Universal Man"
      See: "The Possibilities of Human Growth", Box 35, folder 752
    - "Transatlantic"
      - Holograph, 1929 Jul-Aug (Box 42, Folder 877-79)
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 880-84)
      - Book cover design, 1931 (Box 42, Folder 885)
    - "Unholy"
      - Holograph, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 886)
    - "Values and Fictions"
      - Holograph fragments, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 887-89)
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 890-92)
      - Typescript fragments, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 893)
    - "A Way for a World"
      - Notes, 1936 Oct-Nov (Box 43, Folder 894)
      - Draft, 1936 Nov-Dec (Box 43, Folder 895-98)
      - Draft, 1937 Jan-Feb (Box 43, Folder 899)
      - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 900)
    - "York Beach"
      - Notes, 1928 Aug-Oct (Box 43, Folder 901)
      - Early draft, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 902)
      - Early draft, carbon, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 903)
      - Later draft, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 904)
      - Book cover design, 1931 (Box 43, Folder 905)
      - Publicity, 1930 spring (Box 43, Folder 906)
    - Unidentified book
      - Notes and drafts (Box 43, Folder 907)
  - DRAMA
    - Balo
      - Draft, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 908)
    - "The Colombo-Madras Mail"
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 909)
      - Early draft, 1940 Feb 8 (Box 44, Folder 910)
      - Draft, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 911)
      - Later draft, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 912)
    - "A Drama of the Southwest"
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 913)
      - Holograph, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 914-16)
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 917)
      - Typescript, carbon: 2 copies, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 918-19)
    - "The Gallonwerps"
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 920-23)
      - Holograph: act I, 1927 Nov-Dec (Box 44, Folder 924)
      - Holograph: acts II-III, 1927 Nov-Dec (Box 45, Folder 925-26)
      - Typescript: acts I-III, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 927-29)
      - Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 930-32)
      - Draft variations: act I, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 933)
    - "Man's Home Companion"
      - Draft: typescript and carbon (Box 45, Folder 934)
    - Natalie Mann
      - Draft: typescript, 1922 Feb (Box 45, Folder 935)
    - "Pilgrims Did You Say?"
      See: "The Colombo-Madras Mail", Box 44, folder 909
    - The Sacred Factory
      - Notes and early drafts, 1927, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 936)
      - "First draft", 1927 Sep-Oct (Box 45, Folder 937)
      - Second draft, 1927 (Box 45, Folder 938)
    - "Saint Homo"
      See: The Sacred Factory, Box 45, folder 936
    - "The Saints of Men"
    - "Tourists in Spite of Themselves"
    - Unidentified
      - Notes and drafts, 1935-36 (Box 45, Folder 939)
  - ESSAYS AND LECTURES
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 940)
    - Alfred Stieglitz
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 941)
      - "A Double Portrait": typescript, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 942)
      - "The Hill": Holograph fragments, 1925 Oct (Box 46, Folder 943)
      - "The Hill": "First" and second typescripts (Box 46, Folder 944-45)
      - "Impressions of Stieglitz": typescripts, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 946)
      - "Stieglitz": Holograph, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 947)
    - Doylestown, Pennsylvania
      - "Highways Should be Rightways": drafts, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 948)
      - "The Presence of a Field": Holograph, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 949)
      - "Roads, People, and Principles": drafts, 1939 Jan (Box 46, Folder 950)
      - "Roads, People, and Principles": pamphlet, 1939 (Box 46, Folder 951)
    - Gurdjieff movement
      - "Additional Items"
        See: Box 47, folder 979
      - "America the World"
        See: Box 47, folder 968
      - "Exercises": notes, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 952)
      - "Experiences in the Gurdjieff Work": notes and holograph (Box 46, Folder 953)
      - Georges Gurdjieff: holograph, 1935 Mar (Box 46, Folder 954)
      - "How Can We Make Creative Use?"
        See: Box 47, folder 967
      - "Introduction Talk"
        See: Box 46, folder 955
      - Lectures: outlines, drafts & publicity, 1926-28 (Box 46, Folder 955-58)
      - Lectures: typescripts of I-XII, 1928-29 (Box 46, Folder 959-62)
      - Lectures: typescripts of nos. 1-4, 1930 May (Box 47, Folder 963-66)
      - Lectures: typescripts, 1933 Jan-Mar (Box 47, Folder 967-68)
      - Lectures: typescripts of 1st-6th meeting, 1937 Mar-Apr (Box 47, Folder 969-78)
      - Lectures: outlines and typescript, 1937 Apr-Jun (Box 47, Folder 979-80)
      - "Man in the Making": notes & publicity, 1953 Jul-Oct (Box 47, Folder 981)
      - "A New Group"
        See: Box 46, folder 956
      - "The Possible You"
        See: Box 47, folder 981
      - "Prieuré": holographs, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 982-83)
      - "Prieuré": typescript (Box 47, Folder 984)
      - "Reflexes of Truth": typescript, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 985)
      - "The Reintegration of Ourselves": outline & publicity, 1954 Mar-May (Box 48, Folder 986)
      - "The Relative Understanding of Time": typescript (Box 48, Folder 987)
      - "The Search for Life"
        See: Box 46, folder 957
      - "The Stop Exercise": drafts, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 988)
      - "Words"
        See: Box 46, folder 958
      - Unidentified: notes, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 989)
    - India and China
      - "From Paul Brunton 'Search in Secret India'": typescript (Box 48, Folder 990)
      - "India in the World Situation": outlines (Box 48, Folder 991)
      - "O Shanghai": typescripts, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 992)
      - "Persian Dervish": holograph (Box 48, Folder 993)
      - "They Speak for Themselves": holograph fragments, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 994)
      - "This Is Not India": holograph fragments (Box 48, Folder 995)
    - Literature
      - "The Critic of Waldo Frank": printed in S4N, issues 30-31 (3 copies), 1923-24 (Box 48, Folder 996)
        See also: Box 57, folder 1327
      - "Dimensions in Literature": typescript, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 997)
      - "Halloween": holograph, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 998)